Register to The David Stanley Smith Papers
Yale University Library
- Music, I
  - Choral works, I.G
    - [Pan] (Box 25, Folder 273)
      - [Pan], 1 score (16 p.); 27 cm.
        For soprano solo, women's chorus (SSA), oboe or flute obligato, and piano.
        Words by Elizabeth Barrett Browning.
      - [Pan], 1 score (16 p.); 26 cm.
    - [Pan; arr.], 1 score (28 p.); 35 cm. (Box 25, Folder 273)
      Arranged for women's chorus (SSA) and orchestra.
      Incomplete, choral parts wanting.
      See also: Choral music, women's voices. Selections; and The djinns - vocal score.
    - [Part-songs, mixed voices, op. 34] Choruses for mixed voices / D.S. Smith. -- Published separately: New York: G. Schirmer, 1917. (Box 25)
      Incorrectly labeled op. 33.
      Contents: Matin song / [words by] Thomas Heywood -- Daybreak / [words by] Henry Wadsworth Longfellow -- Morning / [words by] Joanna Baillie.
      Bound with: The fallen star; arr., and Ode for Commencement Day; arr.
    - [Part-songs, mixed voices, op. 34. Daybreak] New York: G. Schirmer, 1917., 1 score (8 p.); 27 cm. (Box 25, Folder 274)
      For chorus (SATB) and piano (only for rehearsal.)
      Words by Henry Wadsworth Longfellow.
    - [Part-songs, mixed voices, op. 34. Matin song] New York: G. Schirmer, 1917., 1 score (7 p.); 27 cm. (Box 25, Folder 274)
      Words by Thomas Heywood.
    - [Part-songs, mixed voices, op. 34. Morning] New York: G. Schirmer, 1917., 1 score (7 p.); 27 cm. (Box 25, Folder 274)
      For chorus (SATB) and piano (for rehearsal only.)
      Words by Joanna Baillie.
    - Part-songs, women's voices, op. 8.
      See: The dark; and Summer winds.
    - Part-songs, women's voices, op. 20.
      See: The wind-swept wheat.
    - [Part-songs, women's voices, op. 35]
      See: A caravan from China; A group of lyrics; and Madrigals, op. 35. No. 6-7.
    - [Psalm 145; arr.] "145th Psalm." 1904 Aug 2
      - [Psalm 145; arr.] "145th Psalm." 1904 Aug 2, 1 score (17 p.); 27 x 35 cm. (Box 25, Folder 275)
        For 2 choruses (SATB each) and orchestra.
        Accompaniment arr. for piano.
      - [Psalm 145; arr.] "145th Psalm." 1904 Aug 2, 5 string parts; 33 cm. (Box 25, Folder 275a)
        Includes violin I-II, viola, violoncello and contrabass
    - [Rhapsody of St. Bernard] The Rhapsody of St. Bernard: for chorus, semi-chorus, and orchestra / poem by Saint Bernard de Clairvaux. 1916 Feb 2, 1 score (260 p.), bound; 46 x 31 cm. (Box 32)
      Latin words.
      Microfilm (master negative) of the above added to Music Library Depost (No. 76) on 1984 Jun.
    - [Rhapsody of St. Bernard; arr.] Rhapsody of St. Bernard: (Jesu Dulcis Memoria): a sacred cantata for chorus, semi-chorus, soli and orchestra / the poem by St. Bernard de Clairvaux / English translation by the composer. -- New York: G. Schirmer, 1918., 1 score (4 leaves, 164 p.), bound; 26 cm. (Box 25)
      Latin and English words, also printed as text on preliminary leaves 2-3.
    - [Rhapsody of St. Bernard. All ye people; arr.] Jesum omnes agnoscite: all ye people: from the cantata "Rhapsody of St. Bernard": for full chorus of women's voices with solo for contralto and piano accompaniment. -- New York: G. Schirmer, 1918., 1 score (11 p.); 26 cm. (Box 25, Folder 276)
      Latin and English words.
    - [Rhapsody of St. Bernard. Jesu, fair flow'r of Mary; arr.] Jesu, fair flow'r of Mary: anthem for four-part chorus of men's voices... -- New York: G. Schirmer, 1918., 1 score (8 p.); 26 cm. (Box 25, Folder 276)
      Arranged for chorus (TTBB) and piano.
    - Russian carols.
      See: J. Miscellaneous works. Sketches.
    - Send forth thy light.
      See: Lux et veritas.
    - [The sleeping priestess]
      - [The sleeping priestess], 1 score (9 p.); 27 cm. (Box 26, Folder 277)
        For women's chorus (SSA), acc.
        Words by Robert Cameron Rogers.
      - [The sleeping priestess], 1 score (7 p.); 42 cm. (Box 32, Folder 3)
        Orchestral score, no voices indicated; it is unclear whether this is an orchestral accompaniment or an arrangement for orchestra alone.
        Sketch in ink (4 p.) crossed out on back.
      - [The sleeping priestess], 5 parts; 34 cm. (Box 26, Folder 277)
        Parts for flute, horn, violin, violoncello, and harp.
        Not same version as orchestral score.
    - [Summer winds] New York: G. Schirmer, 1901., 1 score (15 p.); 27 cm. (Box 26, Folder 278)
      Words by George Darley.
    - [Te Deum laudamus] [1897 Feb?] (Box 26, Folder 279)
      - [Te Deum laudamus] [1897 Feb?], 1 score (28 p.); 34 cm.
        For unison chorus (SATB) and organ.
        Incomplete, pp. 13-27 wanting?
        Extra pp. 9-12 laid in.
      - [Te Deum laudamus] [1897 Feb?], 1 score (10 p.); 27 cm.
    - [The vision of Isaiah] 1927 Aug 25 (Box 32)
      - [The vision of Isaiah] 1927 Aug 25, 1 score (73 p.), bound; 43 cm.
        For contralto and tenor soli, chorus (SATB), and orchestra.
        The text (typescript, 4 p.) and "Corrections in Vision of Isaiah" (holograph, 1 sheet) laid in.
        "Composed 1927" -- card.
        1 microfilm reel housed in box 26.
      - The vision of Isaiah: symphonic poem., 1 score (73 p.), bound; 43 cm.
    - [The vision of Isaiah; arr.] 1927 Aug 1 (Box 26)
      - [The vision of Isaiah; arr.] 1927 Aug 1, 1 vocal score (49 p.), bound; 36 cm.
        The text (typescript, 4 p.) attached to end-paper.
      - [The vision of Isaiah; arr.] 1927 Aug 1, 1 score (49 p.), bound; 35 cm.
    - Why so pale and wan?
    - [The wind-swept wheat (Sketches)], 1 score (20 p.); 35 cm. (Box 26, Folder 280)
      For soprano solo, women's chorus (SSA), and orchestra.
    - [The wind-swept wheat; arr.] New York: G. Schirmer, 1907., 1 score (16 p.); 27 cm. (Box 26, Folder 280)
      Words by Madeline Bridges.
      For soprano solo and women's chorus (SSA) with orchestral acc. arr. for piano.
      Two copies, with different covers.
    - [Yale pageant, 1916] 1916, 1 v. (various paginations) of music; 35 cm. (Box 26, Folder 281)
      Also included is a final chorus, words and music by Jeremiah Savill.
    - [Yale pageant, 1916. Finale], 1 close score (16 p.); 27 cm. (Box 26, Folder 281)
      For chorus.
      Words by T. Lanrason Riggs.
    - The zíncali.
  - Songs, I.H
    - The aeroplane.
      See: Little songs.
    - Alone.
      See: Portraits.
    - April.
      See: Songs, op. 45.
    - Awake, my heart!, 1 score (7 p.); 34 cm. (Box 26, Folder 282)
    - Awake, my love.
      See: Songs, op. 22.
    - The baker-shop.
    - Bird of my lady's bower.
      See: Songs, op. 3.
    - Blue, white, and gold.
    - Caterpillar.
    - Chick-a-dee-dee.
    - The clock.
    - [Come unto Me] Come unto Me: (Matthew 28-30): sacred song with piano accompaniment. -- New York: G. Schirmer, 1910., 1 score (5 p.); 35 cm. (Box 26, Folder 282)
    - A cradle song.
      See: Songs, op. 15; and J. Miscellaneous works. Juvenilia.
    - Crickets.
    - Cupid at cards.
      See: Songs., op. 33.
    - Elegy.
      See: Songs, op. 22. Elegy
    - Evening prayer.
    - Evening song.
      See: Songs, op. 29. Evening song; and Songs, op. 29. Selections.
    - The fairies' Christmas-tree.
    - The fairies' dance.
    - The flower of beauty, op. 29. No. 3.
      See: Songs, op. 29. The flower of beauty; and Songs, op. 29. Selections.
    - Gold and purple.
      See: Songs, op. 15.
    - Hoppy-toad.
    - Houses.
    - I'm the hottest nigger on the map.
    - I wandered lonely.
    - If only thou art true.
      See: Songs, op. 18.
    - [In Gethsemane] In Gethsemane: scripture reading for contralto solo. 1922 Jan 21 (Box 26, Folder 283)
      - [In Gethsemane] In Gethsemane: scripture reading for contralto solo. 1922 Jan 21, 1 score (5 p.); 35 cm.
        Organ acc.
      - [In Gethsemane] In Gethsemane: scripture reading for contralto solo. 1922 Jan 21, 1 score (5 p.); 35 cm.
    - [In praise of the queen of the shepherds], 1 score ([4] p.); 56 cm. (Box 26, Folder 284)
      Words by Edmund Spenser.
    - Jack-in-the-pulpit.
    - Jack-o'-lantern.
    - [Jesus and the children] Jesus and the children: scripture reading for contralto solo. 1922 Jan 29 (Box 26, Folder 285)
      - [Jesus and the children] Jesus and the children: scripture reading for contralto solo. 1922 Jan 29, 1 score (6 p.); 35 cm.
      - [Jesus and the children] Jesus and the children: scripture reading for contralto solo. 1922 Jan 29, 1 score (6 p.); 35 cm.
    - Katy-did.
    - [The lady Alice] 1908 Sep 5, 1 score (7 p.); 36 cm. (Box 26, Folder 286)
      Words by Thomas H. Chivers.
    - [The lady of the lambs] (Box 26, Folder 287)
      - [The lady of the lambs], 1 score (2 p.); 32 cm.
        Words by Alice Meynell.
      - [The lady of the lambs], 1 score (5 p.); 30 cm.
    - Last night.
    - Laziness.
    - [Little songs] Four-and-twenty little songs bound in a book: opus 41 / the verso by Leila Osborne. -- New York: G. Schirmer, 1919., 1 score (47 p.); 30 cm. (Box 26, Folder 288)
      Contents: The aeroplane -- The baker-shop -- Blue, white, and gold -- Caterpillar -- Chick-a-dee-dee -- The clock -- Crickets -- Evening prayer -- The fairies' Christmas-tree -- The fairies' dance -- Hoppy-toad -- Houses -- Jack-in-the-pulpit -- Jack-o'-lantern -- Katy-did -- Last night -- Lullaby -- Madonna -- Slumbersong -- Morning -- My little birch-tree -- Oatmeal -- The papoose -- The pine-wood -- Sailing boats.
    - [Little songs. The fairies' dance], 1 score (3 p.); 35 cm. (Box 26, Folder 288)
    - [Love Thee?], 1 score (4 p.); 34 cm. (Box 26, Folder 289)
      For soprano or tenor and piano.
      Words by Charles Swain.
      Pencil sketch at end.
    - Love's music.
    - Lullaby.
    - Madonna slumber-song.
    - [Meditation], 1 score (4 p.); 35 cm. (Box 26, Folder 290)
    - The message.
      See: Songs, op. 33.
    - Mild is the parting year.
      See: Three songs to texts by Laudor.
    - Morning.
    - Mother, I cannot mind my wheel.
    - My little birch tree.
    - [My pretty rose tree] 1905 Apr 29, 1 score (2 p.); 34 cm. (Box 26, Folder 291)
      Words by William Blake.
    - My Sue.
    - Nod.
    - [Nuptial prayer], 1 score (4 p.); 34 cm. (Box 26, Folder 292)
      For mezzo-soprano, piano, and violin obligato ad libitum.
      Words by D.F. Bloomfield.
    - Oatmeal.
      See: Little-songs.
    - Old Susan.
    - The papoose.
    - The parting hour.
    - [Peace], 1 score ([4] p.); 34 cm. (Box 27, Folder 293)
    - [Peace (Teasdale)], 1 score ([1] sheet); 35 cm. (Box 27, Folder 294)
      On top of p. 1: Teasdale 18.
      Not the same as the above.
    - The pine-wood.
    - [Polly] Polly!: or eyes of old Yale blue / words by Miss Roberta F. Watterson... -- New Haven: Chas. H. Loomis, 1902., 1 score (5 p.); 36 cm. (Box 27, Folder 295)
      See also: J. Miscellaneous works. Juvenilia.
    - [Portraits] Portraits a song-cycle / poems by Walter de la Mare. -- Boston: Oliver Ditson, 1919., 1 score (26 p.); 31 cm. (Box 27, Folder 296)
      For medium voice and piano.
      Contents: I. Nod -- II. Old Susan -- III. Alone -- IV. Rachel -- V. The scarecrow.
      Three copies, one copy bound.
    - Rachel.
    - The rising Of the storm.
      See: Songs, op. 3. The rising of the storm.
    - [Roll out, o song to God] New York: H.W. Gray Co., 1908., 1 score (5 p.); 31 cm. (Box 27, Folder 297)
      For voice and organ.
      Words by Frank Sewell.
    - Romany love song.
    - Roof-tops.
      See: Songs, op. 53.
    - The rose.
      See: Songs, op. 15; and Songs, op. 15. The rose.
    - The rose is weeping for her love.
    - [Rose song] Boston: Oliver Ditson, 1899., 1 score (5 p.); 35 cm. (Box 27, Folder 298)
      Words by Charlotte Fiske Bates.
      See also: Songs. Selections.
    - Ruth.
    - Sailing boats.
    - The scarecrow.
    - Scripture readings.
      See: In Gethsemane; Jesus and the children; and The Transfiguration.
    - Serenade.
      See: Songs, op. 45. Serenade; and J. Miscellaneous works. Juvenilia.
    - She walks in beauty.
    - The shepherd queen.
      See:Songs, op. 33.
    - So sweet is she.
      See: Songs, op. 33; and Songs, op. 33. So sweet is she.
    - So sweet love seemed.
    - [Le soir] 1895 Jan 9, 1 score ([3] p.); 35 cm. (Box 27, Folder 299)
      For soprano and piano.
    - A song of the four seasons.
    - [Songs, op. 3] 1902, 4 scores; 37 cm. (Box 27, Folder 300)
      Published separately: Cincinnati: The John Church Company, 1902.
      Op. 3 added in pencil on title page.
      Contents: Bird of my lady's bower / [words by] Paul Laurence Dunbar -- The rising of the storm / [words by] Paul Laurence Dunbar -- The rose is weeping for her love / [words by] Philip James Bailey -- Still, still within Thee / [words by] Harriet Beecher Stowe.
    - [Songs, op. 3. The rising storm] 1899 Aug 15, 1 score (7 p.); 34 cm. (Box 27, Folder 300)
      For contralto or baritone and piano.
      Words by Paul Laurence Dunbar.
      Op. 3 in pencil on title page.
    - [Songs, op. 15] 1906, 5 scores; 31-35 cm. (Box 27, Folder 301)
      Published separately: New York: G. Schirmer, 1906.
      Contents: A cradle song / [words by] William Blake -- Gold and purple / [words by] George Arnold -- Laziness / [words by] George Arnold -- The rose / [words by] Phoebe Cary.
    - [Songs, op. 15. The rose] 1898 Nov 5, 1 score (4 p.); 35 cm. (Box 27, Folder 301)
    - [Songs, op. 18] Six songs for a medium voice with piano accompaniment. 1907, 7 scores; 31-35 cm. (Box 27, Folder 302)
      Published separately: New York: G. Schirmer, 1907.
      Contents: If only thou art true / words by George Barlow -- Love's music / words by Philip Bourke Mason -- The parting hour / words by Olive Custanse -- Romany love-song / words by Alice E. Gillington -- A song of the four seasons / words by Austin Dobron -- When stars are in the quiet skies / words by Lord Bulwer Lytton.
    - [Songs, op. 18. When stars are in the quiet skies] 1902 Dec 15, 1 score (3 p.); 35 cm. (Box 27, Folder 302)
    - [Songs, op. 22. Elegy] Elegy. (Box 27, Folder 303)
      - [Songs, op. 22. Elegy] Elegy., 1 score (3 p.); 35 cm.
        For high voice and piano.
        Words by Robert Bridges.
        Lacking op. 22, no. 1, "Awake, my love," and op. 22, no. 3, "So sweet love seemed."
      - [Songs, op. 22. Elegy] Elegy., 1 score (133 p.); 34 cm.
    - [Songs, op. 29. Selections] 1907-1908, 2 scores; 33 cm. (Box 27, Folder 304)
      Contents: Evening song / [words by] Sidney Lanier -- The flower of beauty / [words by] George Darley.
      Lacking the second song of op. 29, "Music, when soft voices die."
    - [Songs, op. 29. Evening song] 1908 Feb 5, 1 score (121 p.); 35 cm. (Box 27, Folder 305)
    - [Songs, op. 29. The flower of beauty] 1907 Jul 10 (Box 27, Folder 306)
      - [Songs, op. 29. The flower of beauty] 1907 Jul 10, 1 score (6 p.); 34 cm.
        Holograph signed, in ink with corrections in red ink.
      - [Songs, op. 29. The flower of beauty] 1907 Jul 10, 1 score (5 p.); 32 cm.
      - [Songs, op. 29. The flower of beauty] 1907 Jul 10, 1 score (6 p.); 34 cm.
      - [Songs, op. 29. The flower of beauty] 1907 Jul 10, 1 score (7 p.); 30 cm.
    - [Songs, op. 33] Songs in an old style. 1917 Jan 3 (Box 27, Folder 307)
      - [Songs, op. 33] Songs in an old style. 1917 Jan 3, 5 scores; 36 cm.
        Contents: No. 1. So sweet is she / [words adapted from] Ben Johnson -- No. 2. The shepherd queen / [words by] Edmund Spenser -- No. 3. Tears / anonymous "(from Dowland's Third and Last Book of Songs or Airs," 1603)" -- No. 4. Cupid at cards / [words by] John Lyly -- No. 5 The message / words by Thomas Heywood.
      - [Songs, op. 33] Songs in an old style. 1917 Jan 3, 5 scores; 30 cm.
        Photocopy (negative-reduced) of above holograph.
    - [Songs, op. 33. Selections] Songs in an old style., 5 scores; 36 cm. (Box 27, Folder 308)
      Contents: No. 1. Cupid at cards [2 copies, one originally entitled "Cards and kisses"] -- No. 2. Tears [2 copies] -- No. 3. The message.
    - [Songs, op. 33. So sweet is she], 1 score ([3] p.); 34 cm. (Box 27, Folder 309)
      Words by Ben Johnson.
      Originally with Robin of Sherwood score.
    - Songs, op. 41.
    - [Songs, op. 45] Three songs. 1919 Aug 25 (Box 27, Folder 310)
      - [Songs, op. 45] Three songs. 1919 Aug 25, 1 score (10 p.); 35 cm.
        Contents: Serenade [words by] Aubrey de Vere -- April / [words by] William Watson -- Ruth / [words by] Thomas Hood.
        With: When the wind is low.
      - [Songs, op. 45] Three songs. 1919 Aug 25, 1 score (10 sheets); 28 cm.
    - [Songs, op. 45. Serenade], 1 score (5-p.); 35 cm. (Box 27, Folder 311)
      Op. 45, no. 2 in pencil on title page.
    - [Songs, op. 53. Selections] Three songs. -- Cincinnati: The John Church Company, 1927., 2 scores; 31 cm. (Box 27, Folder 312)
      Contents: Roof-tops / [words by] C.H. Towne -- There will be stars / [words by] Sara Teasdale.
      Lacking "Beyond Rathkelly," one copy bound.
    - [Songs, op. 53. There will be stars] 1925 Jan 17, 1 score (4 p.); 35 cm. (Box 27, Folder 313)
      For low voice and piano.
      Op. 53, no. 2.
    - [Songs. Selections], 16 scores in 1 v., bound; 35 cm. (Box 27, Folder 313)
      Published separately by various publishers.
      Contents: Come unto Me -- Rose song -- Songs, op. 3. No. 1-3 -- Songs, op. 15 -- Songs, op. 18.
    - Songs in an old style, op. 33.
    - [Songs of three ages] Songs of three ages: cycle for high voice with accompaniment of piano / poems by Algernon Charles Swinburne. 1936 Aug 5 (Box 27, Folder 314)
      - [Songs of three ages] Songs of three ages: cycle for high voice with accompaniment of piano / poems by Algernon Charles Swinburne. 1936 Aug 5, 1 score (14 p.); 34 cm.
        "Not a correct copy (other ink copy also marked not correct it is incomplete)" -- title page.
        Contents: Seven years old -- Eight years old -- Nine years old.
      - [Songs of three ages] Songs of three ages: cycle for high voice with accompaniment of piano / poems by Algernon Charles Swinburne. 1936 Aug 5, 1 score (16 p.); 35 cm.
        Holograph signed, in ink with pencil corrections.
        No. 2, "Eight years old," is wanting pp. 6-9.
        Correction clipped to p. 2 and 2 other sheets laid in.
      - [Songs of three ages] Songs of three ages: cycle for high voice with accompaniment of piano / poems by Algernon Charles Swinburne. 1936 Aug 5, 1 score (13 p.); 35 cm.
        "Original version" -- p. 1.
        Page 14 contains a sketch.
    - [Songs of three ages. Nine years old (Sketches)], 3 p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 27, Folder 314)
    - Still, still with Thee.
    - Sweet Clementine.
    - [Sympathy] 1903 Feb 13, 1 score (2 p.); 35 cm. (Box 28, Folder 315)
      Words by Helen Potter.
      Pencil sketch on back.
    - Tears.
    - There will be stars.
      See: Songs, op. 53. There will be stars.
    - [Three songs to texts by Laudor] 1937 Jan 24, 1 score (6 p.); 32 cm. (Box 28, Folder 316)
      Contents: 1. Mother, I cannot mind my wheel -- 2. Sweet Clementine -- 3. Mild is the parting year.
      "(Sketches made many years before)" -- end.
    - [To Etta], 1 score (3 p.) 34 cm. (Box 28, Folder 317)
    - [The Transfiguration] The Transfiguration: scripture narration for baritone (or contralto) solo. 1922 Jan 31 (Box 28, Folder 318)
      - [The Transfiguration] The Transfiguration: scripture narration for baritone (or contralto) solo. 1922 Jan 31, 1 score (6 p.); 35 cm.
      - [The Transfiguration] The Transfiguration: scripture narration for baritone (or contralto) solo. 1922 Jan 31, 1 score (6 p.); 32 cm.
    - [La vie est brève] 1907 May 26, 1 score ([3] p.); 34 cm. (Box 28, Folder 319)
    - When stars are in the quiet skies.
      See: Songs, op. 18; Songs, op. 18. When stars are in the quiet skies; and Songs. Selections.
    - [When the wind...] 1918-1937 (Box 27, Folder 310)
      - [When the wind...] 1918-1937, 1 score (3 p.); 29 cm.
        Words by C.Y.R.
        With: Songs, op. 45.
      - [When the wind...] 1918-1937, 1 score (3 sheets); 28 cm.
    - [When winds are raging] 1901 May 20, 1 score (5 p.); 36 cm. (Box 28, Folder 320)
      Words by Harriet Beecher Stowe.
  - Miscellaneous works, I.J
    - Arrangements
      - Air from Suite in D / J.S. Bach. 1944 Sep 2, 113 sheet of music; 35 cm. (Box 28, Folder 321)
        David Stanley Smith's holograph signed, in pencil.
        Arranged by David Stanley Smith.
      - The Annunciation: Bas-Quercy carol / translated by Edward Bliss Reed / arranged by David Stanley Smith. -- U.S.A.: Stainer Bell (London), 1923., 1 score (4 p.); 26 cm. (Box 28, Folder 322)
      - The children's carol... / from the Provençal / translated by Edward Bliss Reed / harmonized by David Stanley Smith. -- New York: The H. W. Gray Co., 1920., 1 score (3.p.); 26 cm. (Box 28, Folder 322)
        Arr. of Nicolas Saboly's tune.
      - Christmas carols... -- London: Stainer Bell, 1924-1939. -- (Publications of the Carol Society; vol. 1-7, 9-16.), 15 v.; 26 cm. (Box 28, Folder 323-327)
        One to three copies of each.
        Includes: I. Eight traditional French carols. -- II. Eight traditional Christmas carols. -- III. Old French and Franconian carols. -- IV. Old French and German carols. -- V. Old Christmas carols. -- VI. Traditional Christmas carols. -- VII. Old French and Polish carols. -- IX. Traditional Basque and Flemish carols. -- X. Russian, Basque, and Flemish carols. -- XI. Swiss, English and Swedish carols. -- XII. Provençal and Russian carols. -- XIII. Eight old Christmas carols. -- XIV. Old carols for Christmas. -- XV. Flemish and other Christmas carols. -- XVI. Provençal and other Christmas carols.
      - The march of the three kings: old Provençal / translated by Edward Bliss Reed / arranged from Bizet's version by David Stanley Smith. (Box 28, Folder 328)
        - The march of the three kings: old Provençal / translated by Edward Bliss Reed / arranged from Bizet's version by David Stanley Smith., 1 score (8 p.); 26 cm.
        - The march of the three kings: old Provençal / translated by Edward Bliss Reed / arranged from Bizet's version by David Stanley Smith., 1 score (7 p.); 26 cm.
          For men's chorus (TTBB), acc.
      - No rest for Thy head / translated by Edward Bliss Reed / arranged by David Stanley Smith. -- U.S.A.: Stainer Bell Ltd. (London), 1923., 1 score (4 p.); 26 cm. (Box 28, Folder 328)
        Traditional tune.
      - Noël nouvlet / translated by Edward Bliss Reed / arr. by David Stanley Smith. -- New York H.W. Gray Co., 1920., 1 score (5 p.); 26 cm. (Box 28, Folder 328)
      - Noël to honor Mary Mother / harmonized from the version of Léon Roques / by David Stanley Smith / translated by Edward Bliss Reed. -- New York: The H.W. Gray Co., 1920., 1 score (5 p.); 26 cm. (Box 28, Folder 328)
      - Sing we Noël once more / translated by Edward Bliss Reed / Bas-quercy carol / arranged by David Stanley Smith. -- London: Stainer Bell, 1946 (printed in the U.S.A.), 1 score (3 p.); 27 cm. (Box 28, Folder 328)
        For men's chorus, unacc.
      - Sing we Noël once more / Bas-Quercy carol / translated by Edward Bliss Reed / arranged by David Stanley Smith. -- U.S.A.: Stainer Bell, Ltd. (London.), 1 score (3 p.); 26 cm. (Box 28, Folder 328)
      - Ten provençal carols / by Nicolas Saboly of Avignon (1614-1675) / the French and English versions by Edward Bliss Reed / harmonized and edited by David Stanley Smith. -- New York: The H.W. Gray Company, 1918., 1 score (57 p.), bound; 27 cm. (Box 28, Folder 329)
    - Cadenzas, piano (Box 28, Folder 330)
      Cadenza(s) for the concerto in E-flat for two pianofortes by Mozart.
      - Movement I 1922, 3 scores (8, 8, 6 p.) + 1 part; 32-35 cm.
        Holographs signed, in ink and pencil; pencil copy incomplete.
        Three copies of score; part is for Piano II.
      - Finale 1925 Apr 4, 2 scores (8, 8 p.) + 2 parts; 35 cm.
        Two copies of score; parts for Piano I and Piano II.